nait.ca 2013-05-23

# NAIT | NAIT Privacy Policy

The Northern Alberta Institute of Technology ("NAIT") is committed to ensuring the personal privacy of faculty, staff, students, and customers visiting our website. The following information discloses our practices for collecting data, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, why this information is being collected, and how this information is used. The following guidelines were developed with a fundamental respect for our users' right to privacy, and to guide our relationships with our users. NAIT reserves the right to modify our privacy policy at any time. Any such modification will be effective immediately upon posting to the NAIT site.

### Information collected by NAIT

It is important to understand that no personal information such as a person's name, phone number, or email address is ever gathered automatically through the NAIT website. This information is only obtained if it has been provided voluntarily, through email contact, or through an online form.

A web traffic analysis tool is used by NAIT in order to collect anonymous information from visits to our website. The data we attain by using this software helps us understand the traffic patterns and types of technology our visitors use. Monthly statistics are generated from this content so that we can continually improve our audience's online experience. The information collected cannot be associated with any specific individual and no attempt is made to identify particular users browsing the site.

The information we collect helps us identify:

  * The Internet domain and IP address from which you access the NAIT website.
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access the site.
  * The pages that were visited.
  * The date and time the site was accessed.
  * Popular search phrases.

### Use of information

All personal information that is collected is managed in accordance with the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act. This means that, at the point of collection, you will be informed that your personal information is being collected; the purpose for which it is being collected, and that you have a right to access the collected information. NAIT will not reveal any personal information that users provide to any third party without the users' permission. Access to personal information is restricted to those NAIT employees who require this information in order to provide requested products or services. Upon request, NAIT will remove users (and their information) from our database or permit them to "opt-out" of any further email newsletters or contact.

### Cookies

Some of the web pages and applications on this site use cookies. Cookies are short and simple text files that are sent through a web browser and stored on your system. The NAIT website uses these files to keep track of and store information so the user can accomplish set tasks without having to enter the same content multiple times. Cookies are never used by NAIT in an attempt to capture personal information about our users. If you are concerned about cookies, refer to the help menu in your browser for information on how to disable cookies. Browsers may also be enabled to notify you when a website is attempting to send a cookie to your machine.

### Transactions where information enters a system of records

Where personal information is provided that enters a system of records, it is collected in compliance with section 33 (c) of the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act. NAIT collects, creates and maintains information for the purposes of admission, registration and other activities directly related to its educational programming. Information collected is only kept for the length of time necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected.
